Guide to the Rice University Office of Vice-President for Enrollment records UA 182
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Office of Vice-President for Enrollment records
1993-2005
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University. Office of Vice President for Enrollment
UA 182
7.5 Linear Feet (15 boxes)
These records were generated by the Office of the VP for Enrollment from 1993 to 2005. The office oversees the Office of Admissions, Enrollment Operations and Student Financial Services. The record types include statistics, policies and procedures, planning and management studies, and general information.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of Enrollment oversees the offices of admission, enrollment operations and student financial services at Rice University.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records reflecting the daily business of the Rice University Office of Enrollment, including expense reports for faculty travel and for department spending, application records from potential faculty and graduate students, and documentation on incoming students.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is restricted for privacy reasons. Permission to access the material must be granted in writing from the Office of the Vice President for Enrollment.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please contact the Woodson Research Center for more information: woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred on 8-10-07 by Melissa Kean.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
reports; documents
- Series I: Subject files, A-M, 159798
  - Admission Statistics, 1999-2000, 94987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admission Statistics, 2000-2001, 94988 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Admission Statistics, 2001-2002, 94990 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Admission Statistics, 2002-2003, 94992 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Admission Statistics, 2005, 94994 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Admission Statistics, 2006, 94996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Admission Process Summary, 2003, 94997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Admission Strategic Planning, 2005, 94998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Admission Strategic Planning, 2005-2006 - Mailings, 94999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Admission Strategic Planning, 2005-2005 – Northeast US, 95000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Application Statistics, 2005, 95001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Best Education for the Money" 1997 (VHS tape), 95002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees & Administration Pictorial Directory, 2005, 95003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees Enrollment Retreat Briefing Book, 2000, 95004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees – Academic Affairs Committee, 2005, 95005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Budget, FY 2006, 95006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Budget, FY 2004, 95007 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Budget, FY 2003, 95008 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Budget, FY 2002, 95010 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Budget, FY 2002, 95012 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Budget, FY 2001, 95013 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Budget, FY 2000, 95014 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Budget, FY 1999, 95015 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Budget, FY 1997, 95016 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Budget, FY 1996, 95017 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Budget, FY 1994-1995, 95018 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Budget, FY 1993-1994, 95019 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Budget Development, 2002, 95020 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Budget Requests, 2001, 95021 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - COFHE publication: Minority Faculty at COFHE Institutions, 2004, 95022 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - COHFE correspondence, 2000-2001, 95023 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - COHFE correspondence, 1998-1999, 95024 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - COHFE Enrolled Student Survey 2003, 95025 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - College Board: Profile for Rice University, 1998, 95026 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Combined Survey, 2005 (Appendix only), 95027 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Common Data Set, 2004-2005, 95028 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Consolidated Financial Statements, Rice University – 2004-2005, 95029 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Data Cleanup Project Proposal, 2006, 95030 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Donor Honor Roll directory, 2000-2001, 95031 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Endowed Scholarship Process Audit Documentation Binder, 2003, 95032 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Endowed Scholarship Process Review, 2003; folder 1 of 2, 95034 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Endowed Scholarship Process Review, 2003; folder 2 of 2, 95035 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Enrollment Challenge Powerpoint Presentation, 2005, 95036 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Enrollment Review 1999-2003, 95037 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Enrollment Division Data Book, 1999-2005, 95038 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Enrollment Division Data Book, 1999-2003, 95039 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Enrollment Management and Strategic Use of Financial Aid Review, 95040 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Enrollment Management Task Force, 95041 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Enrollment Planning 2003-2004, 95042 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Enrollment Planning 2001-2002, 95043 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment Strategic Planning, 95044 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting: May 13, 2005, 95045 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Financial Aid for Fall 2005, 95046 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Financial Aid Scholarships: Honorary No-Need Scholarships, 95047 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Financial Services: Merit Awards (Owl/Trustee), 95048 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Financial Services Statistics 2000, 95049 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - International Students and Scholars 2006, 95050 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - JJS Report 1999, 95051 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - [Reflections on a Summer with] Leadership Rice, 95052 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Leebron, David (President), 95053 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Maguire Project, 95054 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Marketing Opportunity & Image Analysis 1996, 95055 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
  - Matriculation Speech 2004-2005, 95059 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Merit Awards: Engineering, 95060 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Merit: SFS Data, 95061 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Merit Strategy, 95062 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Series II: Subject files, N-Z, 159799
  - Non-Applicant, Non-Enrolling and Enrolling Student Studies, 95063 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Non-Applicant, Non-Enrolling and Enrolling Student Studies, 95064 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Non-Applicant, Non-Enrolling and Enrolling Student Studies: Appendix, 95066 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 2005 Non-Applicant Study, 95067 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Owl Scholars, 95069 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Pricing, 95070 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Registrar's Office: Report to the President: Enrollment 1980-84, 95071 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Registrar's Office: Distribution of Grades 1986-1989, 95072 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Registrar's Office: Distribution of Grades 1977-85, 95073 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Recruitment and Awarding Results Fall 2002-2003, 95074 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - [Review of] Recruitment and Awarding Results Fall 2002-2003, 95075 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Report to the President 2005, 95076 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Report to the President 2004, 95077 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Report to the President 2003, 95078 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Report to the President Fall 2002, 95079 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Report to the President: Registrar's Office 1977-1980, 95080 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Report to the President: Registrar's Office 1973-1976, 95081 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Rice 101: Administrative Career Training Program, 95082 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Rice Alumni Volunteers for Admission, 95083 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Rice: General Information, 95084 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Rice University: Volume 5, 95085 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Royall & Company, 95086 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Royall & Company Reports 2005-2006, 95087 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Scholarships 1999 (all-inclusive), 95088 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Scholarships 1998 (combined), 95089 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Scholarships: Baker, James A. Scholarship, 95090 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Scholarships: Brown, E. Vandiver Scholarship, 95091 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Scholarships: Caesar Scholarship, 95092 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Scholarships: Class Scholarships, 95093 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Scholarships: Edwards, T.C. Scholarship, 95094 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Scholarships: Haynie, Lillian Scholarship, 95095 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Scholarships: Honors Scholarship (non-minority), 95096 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Scholarships: Johnson, Gaylord Scholarship Fund, 95097 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Scholarships: Jordan, Barbara Scholarship, 95098 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Scholarships: Lancaster Memorial Scholarship, 95099 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Scholarships: Martin, Helen South Scholarship, 95100 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Scholarships: Maurin Mathematics Scholarship, 95101 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Scholarships: McCardell Scholarship, 95102 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Scholarships: Meredith, Byron Scholarship Fund, 95103 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Scholarships: Metz Scholarship, 95104 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Scholarships: Miscellaneous, 95105 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Scholarships: Mobil Scholars, 95106 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Scholarships: Pearlstone Scholarship, 95107 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Scholarships: Presidential Scholarship (non-minority), 95108 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Scholarship Recipients 2003, 95109 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Scholarships: Rice, William Marsh Scholarship 1994, 95110 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Scholarships: Roy, Max Scholarship, 95111 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Scholarships: Soon, Berda & Charles Memorial Scholarship Fund, 95112 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Scholarships: Tandy Technology Scholars, 95113 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Scholarships: Williams, Don E. (Scholarship Sponsor), 95114 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Scholarships: Wilson, R. Howard & Elizabeth P. Endowed Scholarship Fund, 95115 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - School Profiles, 95116 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - Search Program Summary/Annual Report 2005, 95118 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Search Program Summary 2004, 95119 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Spring Search Program 1999, 95120 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Spring Search Summary 1999, 95121 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - SFS Loan Policy, 95122 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Statistics 2004-2005, 95123 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Studentship: Baker, Graham, 95124 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Tuition Exchange Study, 95125 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Tuition: Strategies and Analyses, 95126 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - UG Admission Office Stats 2000, 95127 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Value(s) Based Pricing in Higher Education 2003, 95128 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Year in Review 2003-2004, 95129 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Series III: Retreat
  - Retreat notebook, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 10)